Albert Edelmann

Frontend Developer

Former 11 years experienced Production Engineer that changed career path to Web Development. I believe that high performance indicates a good piece of engineering, it's one of my top goals. I am target oriented, proactive, adventurous, assiduous, animated and passionate by learning new technologies. This CV was build with CVFY, my graduation project.

- ☑ albert.edelmann@gmail.com
- /www.linkedin.com/in/albert-edelmann
- # /ajedelmann.github.io/portfolio

01742087356

- albert.edelmann
- github.com/AJEdelmann

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineering Consultant

Petrobras, SGS UK, E&IM and Embratecno

Aug / 2016 - Dec / 2018 Achivements / Tasks

Berlin, Germany

 As a Consultant Engineer, I follow-up and testify the quality tests of equipments and materials on behalf of my customers in factory shops located in Europe and Asia.

Expediting and VQS Manager

Hatch

Feb / 2014 - Jul / 2016 Sao Paulo, Brazil Achivements / Tasks

- Lead technical negotiations with suppliers in order to mitigate quality, costs and schedule impacts; - Issue and release Technical Specifications, Histogram and Working Plan; - Coordinate the Expediting, VQS and Logistics team during the whole Post Award phase at project Hydro-Alunorte; -

Manage Expediting & VQS services contract

Procurement Team Lead

Consórcio UFN3

May / 2012 - Jan / 2014 Sao Paulo, Brazil Achivements / Tasks

- Coordinated the expediting and inspection team, in order to ensure that all the hundreds of suppliers linked to this Project complied with the contract terms as well as with the numerous Petrobras Quality requirements. - Coordinated and performed Kick of Meetings at national and international vendors in order to align them with project directives and avoid losing control of schedule for each supply step

SKILLS



PROJECTS

CVFY (12/2019 - 03/2020)

A full-stack website that provides professional CV and Cover Letter templates where the user can import their data from LinkedIn, build their CV and Cover Letter and style it with our may design features, save the document online, convert it to pdf and more.

Main technologies used: React, Context API, Node.js and MongoDB.

Roman Calculator (02/2020)

A frontend application that calculate roman numbers builded with React and tested with Jest.

Jammming (01/2020)

A website builded with React, fetching data from Spotify API to allow users to search the Spotify library, create a custom playlist, then save it to Spotify account.

React Todo App (12/2019 - 01/2020)

Full-stack application builded with: React and Redux (frontend), fetching data from my own API builded with Node.js and MongoDB (backend).

React Ravenous (12/2019)

Builded with React, Node.js and fetching data from Yelp API.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Procurement Contract Specialist

Camargo Corrêa

Jan / 2007 - Apr / 2012 Sao Paulo, Brazil Achivements / Tasks

- During 5 years of work on this Brazilian multinational company, I was involved in 3 major projects:

2010 to 2012 – International Expediter Lead Project:

RNEST (Oil&Gas Refinery Construction) Client:

PETROBRAS 2009 to 2010

- Procurement Coordinator Project: UÍGE

(Energy Transmission line Construction) Client: ANGOLA

GOVERNMENT 2007 to 2009
Procurement Analyst Project: ALUMAR

(Alluminium Refinery Expansion) Client: ALCOA

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development

DCI Digital Career Institute GmbH

03 / 2019 - 04 / 2020 Berlin, Germany

Production Engineering - Bachelor Degree

Unifass

01 / 2009 - 12 / 2014 Brazi

BachareladoPublicidade, Propaganda e Marketina

Universidade Presbiteriana Mackenzie
07 / 2000 - 12 / 2004

Brazi

PROJECTS

Music-chords-API (11/2019)

RESTful API of music chords using Node, Express, Puppeteer and Mongoose.

Piano Player (08/2019 - 10/2019)

Created with pure JavaScript. It can be played with computer keyboard. Have fun testing.

Rhyme Generator (06/2019 - 07/2019)

In this project I use the boilerplate code for an AJAX request using XHR object on Datamuse API to search for words that rhyme.

CERTIFICATIONS

PMI - Project Management (corporative course at Camargo Correa)

ACHIEVEMENTS

Nominated class tutor during my Full Stack Development course at DCI.

Won the second prize at DCI Hackathon 2019.

LANGUAGES

English German
Full Professional Proficiency B2 certificated

Portuguese Spanish

Mother tongue Bilingual Proficiency